So you had a look at build with react and react.rocks,
Wic spojrzae na build, by zareagowa i zareagowa. Skay, teraz odejdmy od
now let's move away from demo projects and so on
projektw demonstracyjnych i tak dalej, a
and let's instead have a look at gatsbyjs.
zamiast tego rzumy okiem na gatsbyjs.
Now gatsbyjs is actually a library building up on react, just like nextjs did, gatsbyjs serves a
Teraz gatsbyjs jest tak naprawd bibliotek budujc si na reakcj, tak jak robi to nextjs,
different purpose though and it's a pretty exciting library
gatsbyjs suy jednak innym celom i jest
I'll be honest with you. Gatsbyjs is a library that allows you to build static web sites with react.
to do ekscytujca biblioteka, z ktr bd szczery. Gatsbyjs to biblioteka, ktra pozwala na tworzenie statycznych stron internetowych z reakcj.
Now what's a static website? A static website is a page which uses only html, javascript and css,
Co to jest statyczna strona internetowa? Statyczna strona to strona, ktra uywa tylko html, javascript i
well that's true for normal, react single page application too but a static site also has one special
css, c, to prawda w przypadku zwykej, reagujcej aplikacji na pojedyncz stron, ale statyczna strona rwnie ma jedn
thing going for it,
specjaln rzecz, ktra si
you normally don't use react router there, you don't use it directly at least,
tam dzieje, zwykle nie uywasz routera reagowania, nie uywaj go bezporednio, a zamiast tego masz
instead what you have is you have a folder structure where each folder has an index.html file, and the according
struktur folderw, w ktrej kady folder ma indeks. plik html i odpowiednie zasoby nalece
assets belonging to the file in it.
do pliku w nim zawartego.
Now the cool thing with that is that you really build websites like you did in the 90s or around that
Teraz fajne jest to, e naprawd tworzysz witryny podobne do tych z lat
time but you're using react, you're building this as a react app and gatsbyjs, this technology, this
90. lub mniejszych, ale uywasz reagowania, budujesz to jako aplikacj reagowania i gatsbyjs, ta technologia, ta
library then actually does the rest for you,
biblioteka faktycznie robi Odpoczynek dla
splits everything up and upon a certain command, generates this folder structure where you got a couple
ciebie, dzieli wszystko i na okrelon komend, generuje t struktur folderw, skd
of folders with html files in there based on the react that you built.
masz kilka folderw z plikami html na podstawie reakcji, ktr zbudowae.
You can learn more about it on gatsbyjs.com,
Moesz dowiedzie si wicej o tym na gatsbyjs. com, to niesamowita
it's an amazing library and it actually would provide enough content for its own course.
biblioteka, ktra w rzeczywistoci zapewni wystarczajc ilo treci dla wasnego kursu.
Now I don't have such a course right now,
Teraz nie mam takiego kursu, moesz
you could start with the docs here though to learn how to use it and definitely play around with
zacz od dokumentw tutaj, ale aby dowiedzie si, jak z niego korzysta i
it a bit to learn more about how it works and if it makes sense for you, comparable alternatives mentioned
na pewno troch si z nim pogodzi, aby dowiedzie si wicej o tym, jak to dziaa i czy ma
on the features page of gatsbyjs would be Jekyll
sens dla Ciebie, porwnywalne alternatywy wymienione na stronie funkcji
but there you don't use react or content management systems like Wordpress,
gatsbyjs to Jekyll, ale tam nie uywasz systemw reagowania ani systemw
there however, you are stuck to writing some server side code too,
zarzdzania treci, takich jak Wordpress, ale musisz te napisa kod po
you need a SQL database and all that stuff. Gatsbyjs works with react and that offers quite a lot
stronie serwera, potrzebujesz bazy danych SQL i tego wszystkiego. Gatsbyjs dziaa z reakcj i oferuje
of advantages.
wiele zalet.
So consider this for your next project,
Zastanw si wic nad kolejnym projektem, zapoznaj
check out the docs and the features page on their page to learn if it's the right choice for you
si z dokumentami i stron funkcji na swojej stronie, aby dowiedzie si, czy jest to
and once you decide that it's interesting to you, feel free to dive into it.
waciwy wybr, a gdy uznasz, e jest to dla ciebie interesujce, nie krpuj si.
I wanted to make you aware of it because it's a really amazing project.
Chciaem Ci o tym poinformowa, poniewa jest to naprawd niesamowity projekt.